MÁRCIO JOSÉ GURKA JÚNIOR

Ponta Grossa, Paraná, CEP 84053-220 | 55(42)9982-4591 | marciogurkajr@gmail.com | LinkedIn: https://br.linkedin.com/in/marciogurkajr | GitHub: https://github.com/marciogurka | Website: http://www.marciogurka.com

Introdution

Born in 1995, worked as Backend developer intern at the Technology Datacenter of Ponta Grossa State University. Also worked as UI/UX App Designer and Web Developer at The Royal College of Physicians & Surgeons of United. Nowadays working as a Full-Stack Developer and innovation researcher at DF Systems, a Startup located at Ponta Grossa, Paraná, Brazil. Working remotely as a Front-End Development Intern at SA Trails, located at Austin, Texas. Finishing his bachelor's Computer Engineering degree of the Ponta Grossa State University. Works as project advisor and Full-Stack Developer at the Computer Engineering Junior Company of the Ponta Grossa State University.

Programming Skills

Strong skills in: PHP, JavaScript, GIT, AngularJS, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Twitter Boostrap, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Sybase, Laravel, Zurb Foundation, Ionic Framework, Material Design Familiar with: Python, MongoDB, WebRTC, C, Java, Docker, NodeJS, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator,

ExpressJS

General Skills

Skills like: OOP, Web Development, database design and maintenance, software development, teamwork, entrepreneurship, research, innovation, leadership, creativity, reversal engineering, image manipulation (Adobe Photoshop), prototyping, proative, good worker, management.

Professional Experience

Full Stack Development Intern, 3/2016 to Present – DF Systems, Ponta Grossa, Paraná Innovation projects in Javascript, NodeJS, Laravel, AngularJS and Zurb Foundation; Creation of new products and services. Systems maintenance and development.

Backend Development Intern, 6/2014 to 2/2015 – Information Technology Hub of Ponta Grossa State University, Ponta Grossa, Paraná

Improved Backend developer of Institutional Research Management System; Maintenance of academic systems; Technical support for users; Improved and maintaned institutional databases systems.

Innovation Researcher and Developer, 6/2015 to 2/2016 – DF Systems, Ponta Grossa, Paraná Innovation projects in Javascript, NodeJS; Creation of new products.

Volunteer programmer and project advisor, 7/2015 to Present – EJEC (Junior Company of Computer Engineering), Ponta Grossa, Paraná

Consultancy and development of technological solutions.

 $\label{lem:conditional} \textbf{Volunteer App Developer/UX Researcher \& Designer/ Web Developer, } 6/2016 \ to \ 8/2016 - RCPSUS \ (Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons - US), Detroit, USA$

Consultancy and development of technological solutions.

Front-End Development Intern, 6/2016 to present – SA Trails, LLC, Austin, Texas

Front-End Development of the tool, migrating from Bootstrap Framework to Material Design, using NodeJS, ExpressJS, Docker, Material Design and AngularJS.

Volunteer, 1/2013 to 12/2015 – Computer Museum UEPG, Ponta Grossa, Paraná

Creation of products using recyclable materials of computers, production of educational robotic workshops.

Education

SANT'ANA HIGH SCHOOL AND UNIVERSITY – Ponta Grossa, Paraná Computer Science Technician, 12/2011
Improved Programming Skills; Hardware Maintenance

PONTA GROSSA STATE UNIVERSITY – Ponta Grossa, Paraná **Bachelor's degree Computer Engineering,** Expected to 12/2016

Emphasis in Software Development, Programming Languages and Hardware Building

PARANÁ FEDERAL TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY – Ponta Grossa, Paraná **English (Intermediate),** 12/2013 Improved English Language. Workload: 320 hours

INFLUX ENGLISH SCHOOL – Ponta Grossa, Paraná **English (Advanced)**, Expected to 06/2017 Improved English Language

PONTA GROSSA STATE UNIVERSITY – Ponta Grossa, Paraná **Software Build Management**, 8/2014 Improved knowledgment of GIT skills. Workload: 20 hours

PONTA GROSSA STATE UNIVERSITY – Ponta Grossa, Paraná Laravel – AngularJS Software Development, 11/2015 Improved AngularJS and Laravel skills. Workload: 20 hours

* Several other courses involving programming languages, software management, people management, project management and innovation.

Other Interests

Entrepreneurship, learning languages, agile software development, music, technology, innovation, books, computing, games, photography, sports, learning programming languages, running, traveling